installing harvester is a very easy task
you just need to download and install the iso we provide
we will create a new cluster
then we will select the disk
we will provide the network configuration
including the host name
the management network interface
the dns server
and the custom token this token will be
used to secure your harvester deployment
we need to provide the password to
access to nodes
as well as the ntp configuration
please note that ntp is critical for a
successful harvester installation
after you verify the provide parameters
you are ready to install harvester
it will perform some automatic tasks
and after a few minutes
your harvester installation
will be ready