harvester can also be managed from the
standard rancher console
you just need to navigate to the virtualization management section and
you will get a very similar experience
that the one you get when managing
harvester directly
there are just a couple of differences as you can note
namespaces are also referred as projects
and you can configure
rancho attack from this interface
as harvester is yet another provider for rancher
you can provision your own rke and rk2 clusters
you will follow the same procedure as you would do for any other provider
you can of course create your own template for your harvester deployment
please note that the options are very similar to any infrastructure provider
you can of course select multiples vms
and you just need to make sure you select harvester as your provider
in harvester you can also deploy your a key and your k3s clusters
you will pull all the options directly from the provider