hi the courser here
i want to show how to add a disk to a running vm on harvester
this comes after a demo i did during the cube versus summit 2022 and during the demo i did one error
i went to the config here on volumes
and i tried to add an existing volume
then unchecked restart now and click save so
if i do it actually just to show you what is the error
here i will pick my cuber submit disk
and everything else is set up for me
and then when i will click save it gave me the error
and i thought it was like the demo gods against me well
no what i did wrong is that i need to add a volume directly from the menu here
where i will call it cube vert summit disk for example
and then i will pick up my disk that is unassigned
I will click apply
and if i go to the volumes now i can see that it's attached to the vm
so back to the vm now
what we will see here for now is i don't have the disk so
if i refresh the settings here now it sees the disk
and if i go to the disk manager and i refresh also
i will have a new disk appearing in few seconds
and actually it's here sorry
and here i can see my 10 gigabit uh disk so
if i put it online
i initialized it with gpt
and finally i can create a volume out of it with the full space
i will just keep the defaults for the demo
and now we can see the disk so here it is how to add odd plug volume