hello everyone today we'll be showing you a very cool demo composed of rancher desktop
microsoft visual studio code
or real and nice bci container image
and a very cool remote containers from Microsoft
so get ready
let's start with rancher desktop
rancher desktop is a software that provides you with container management and Kubernetes on your desktop
run your desktop works on apple, windows and linux
why using rancher desktop because as i told you
it offers you container management so you can build push and pull your containers
you have a nice and easy way to interact with Kubernetes
you have your own local kubernetes environment
and it is built on projects like k3s qctl and more known projects
it will make the way you interact with kubernetes easy and simple
you'll see
now it's time to introduce SUSE container images
So our base container image or bci based and suse linux enterprise server 15.
this is a low footprint secure image
you can pull it with podman with docker whatever tool you want
it is supported on many different architectures as you can see here in the in the webpage
and it's definitely going to make your life easier
now the visual studio code remote containers extension
this is a very cool feature from visual studio code
this allows you to set up a docker container as a local development environment
so you can run the same environment wherever you need
so basically you connect your local environment with a container
and you share the code in that container and run it there
to do this we're going to use this chart made by Matt Farina our engineer
and afterwards we'll use this hello world application made in go
first of all let's deploy the application using the helm chart
so let's go to install with the chart we saw in the repo
so helm install name whatever you want
parameters and content of the chart
now we're going to forward the port so we can access the application
it's a hello world web application
so accessing the local port 8080
we'll see that says hello rancher desktop
that's okay
now let's going to move on to the real code of the application
so let's open code visual studio code from our repo
so just code the path and it opens we'll see that offers the option to run is a container
this is what i introduced you previously the remote container feature
so you can use a container as a development environment
so we just need to add this dev container folder that contains a json and a docker file that will be used
in the let's say development container we pop up
so here in the terminal we have the container we can do an ls
and now we're going to run our application
so it's a go application "go run" whatever
and it's going to start
and when it starts visual studio code
you will detect that is running on the background and offers you to open the browser so
easy simple and very nice
now let's change the application
we need for instance instead of saying hello rancher desktop
we need that it says hello world
so we're going to change it here directly
and we're going to run the container again
this time in the boot mode and
you‘re gonna see that offers again to open the browser and now it says hello world
so it can't be easier
you can use that same container for any environment you use
but there's another docker file is outside that previous dev container folder
and this is a common docker file
that is going to run a scratch container with this very same application
and we are going to see the difference when we build an new image using that docker file
so we're building the version 2 0 2 0 we build the container
and now if we check the images
we're going to see something amazing
The visual studio code let's say development container is huge
why is huge because it needs a lot of libraries and stuff that is included there
however let's see our scratch container is just six MB
it's tiny it's very very very small
now what we're going to do is to update our helm chart
remember we deployed the helm chart
so we're going to deploy our helm chart with this new container we build
or with this image we built sorry
we're going to tag it with the proper tag
and we're going to see that the application runs again
and again it's the new application it will say again hello world instead of hello rancher desktop
so basically what i'm showing you here it's a very easy to have environments on different let's say
tools with different solutions to run and test your software
so that's all for today i hope you enjoy this demo