hello welcome to a new release of rancher desktop
but what is rancher desktop rancher's desktop is a nice piece of software
that provides you a local environment to develop containers and workloads
that runs on mac on windows and linux
it offers you container management
you can build push and pull your images
it offers you a local kubernetes where you can test your microservices and workloads
it is built on projects like K3s and containerd
today we're going to cover Rancher Desktop 1.3
as you can see the basic UI didn't change much
version 1.3.0 so let's overview the ui
in this part here nothing or not much change
but there are news you're going to see all the new stuff coming
so at the moment let's check the images in the cluster already deployed
so we can see that basically are the images that K3s used to work
but now let's take a look how we can pull an image from Rancher Desktop
let's pull a BCI image
so as you see you paste the URL
you pull the image
but you can do much more than that
we find the image there
we can push it to a registry
or we can scan for CVEs
as BCI is a very secure image, we won't find any CVE
that's cool let's keep going
so we can configure the kubernetes as we saw, we selected containerd
so we need to use nerdctl, let's make a test
let's run an alpine image
and let's connect to the container
and perform a basic ls command
and after this
we will see that however we were working on the cli
we'll see the image in the namespace default in the Rancher Desktop UI
so again we are scanning for vulnerabilities
looks like everything is in place
perfect
so now let's see the shiny new dashboard yeah
now rancher desktop has a dashboard
a really cool one
if you are used to rancher
you will see something that is familiar to you
so let's check what we can see and do from this dashboard
first of all
basic stuff, namespaces, nodes
so it's a development environment, one node
control plane and also worker
we can see the information
we can see what is going on on that node
we can see a huge amount of information
DaemonSets, deployments in the cluster
we can see jobs, StatefulSet, Pods
we can click delete something
we can redeploy
we can interact what would be seen inside of the cluster
so we can check the pod
see this pod is not ready
we can move on to another pod
so for instance the load balancer, traffic
so we can from here execute a shell
we can connect to the pod
and perform operations inside that pod
just from this new dashboard that's very cool
i think for me it's very cool
it's easy and it's really intuitive
this is great
we can see related resources also
we can see the services on the cluster
which services are deployed
which ports are using
a lot of information okay
but we don't stop here
we can also create and expose services from the dashboard
so again very cool we can create our own service
load balancers like in this case
we can create node for whatever we need
we can do it just from here
rancher desktop is about making your life easier
that's what this dashboard does
makes your life easier
so we can see a lot of information more ip addresses
selectors, we can select affinity, labels
all what you can expect from kubernetes
but from a single and nice UI
we can see also the storage, storage classes
persistent volumes, ConfigMaps
and almost any kind of resource you can imagine
you can find it here
k3s resources for instance
add-ons the helm charts that are being used inside k3s that is what we are using at the moment
we can access and interact with the role-based access of the cluster
so you can see cluster roles, user roles
you can create, destroy, interact
again making your life easier
so we can see also the nodes
and the storage classes
among the information we can see the
traffic IngressRoutes
we can see what is inside
api resources services you know
with Rancher you can do anything through the API
that's all