if you're responsible for securing your organization's containerized deployments
you might be the victim of some risky assumptions regarding kubernetes security
many assume their cloud provider or other supplemental technologies will cover everything needed for kubernetes security
but they don't
with kubernetes being open source and notoriously hard to implement and understand
you can be left blind to what's happening in your network
that's where NeuVector comes in
as one of the only network security experts in the container space
NeuVector provides unmatched visibility automation
and control of all kubernetes network traffic and container processes
with NeuVector you gain comprehensive vulnerability scanning
to identify flaws throughout the application life cycle
automated behavioral learning to discover container processes inspect and validate network traffic
generate security policy as code
and enable virtual patching to prevent attacks
network security to prevent malware or attackers from traversing the entire network
including real-time blocking of zero day threats
and deep packet inspection for layer 7 visibility of all kubernetes defined and undefined network traffic
and compliance, the only solution to meet specific data security and network segmentation requirements for pci dss soc 2 and gdpr
essential for any company handling credit cards or personal and private information
as your trusted security advisor, NeuVector will help you meet and exceed the standards for container security
just as we've done for many leading companies across financial services insurance healthcare the public sector and e-commerce
kubernetes needs protection
NeuVector is the only solution you can rely on
to automate granular security processes and policies to protect your container deployments
from both known and unknown threats